Guide to the Papers of Harmon Hendricks Goldstone 1906-1979 (bulk 1966-1979) MS 256
New-York Historical Society
- Series III. Scrapbooks
  - City Planning Commission 3, 1963-1966 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - City Planning Commission Personal File, 1963-1974 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Beginning of Landmarks Preservation Commission, 1961-1970 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Landmarks Preservation Commission: Law, Calendars, Designated Historic Districts, Proposed Historic Districts, Misc., 1965-1975 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Landmarks Preservation Commission, 1970-1973 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Landmarks Preservation Commission: Letters and Clippings Regarding His Resignation from Landmark Preservation Commission and Copy of Supreme Court Decision in Grand Central Case, 1973-1978 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Beginning of Landmarks Preservation Commission - Personal File, 1961-1975 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - History Preserved: A Guide to New York City Landmarks and Historic Districts, 1974-1980 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Wedding Scrapbook of Goldtone's parents (Aline May Lewis and Lafayette Anthony Goldstone), 1906-1908 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Series IV. Clippings and Memorabilia
  This series contains newspaper and magazine clippings along with memorabilia both personal and professional. The professional items are arranged in roughly chronological order based on the period of Goldstone's career. The personal items are included at the end of the series.
  Among the professional materials are descriptions of some of Goldstone's architectural projects such as the Aquatic Birds Building at the Bronx Zoo; press coverage of several of his dissenting opinions while on the City Planning Commission; copies of a speech transcript supporting the proposed Landmarks Preservation Bill; a photograph of Goldstone with Mayor John V. Lindsay; and a program commemorating the Landmarks Preservation Commission's acceptance of the New York State Award, given in 1972 by the New York Council on the Arts.
  - Architecture, 1964,n.d. (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - City Planning Commission, 1962-1966 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Landmarks Preservation Commission Duplicate Clippings, 1964-1975 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Fraunces Tavern, 1967-1978 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Mayor's Art Award, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Better Subways, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Municipal Arts Society, 1961-1980 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - American Institutes of Architects, 1968-1985 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Wyckoff House Association, 1982-1984 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Memberships, 1961-1982 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Personal Clippings and Memorabilia, 1916-1969, undated (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Personal Clippings and Memorabilia, 1970-1980, undated (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Personal Clippings and Memorabilia, 1980-1988, undated (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - 40th/50th Anniversary Edition, Lincoln School, 1968, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Letterheads and Mastheads, undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - David Kotlar Binders, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 6)
- Series V. Publications, Speeches, and Indices
  This series includes an original manuscript of Goldstone's book,History Preserved: New York City Landmarks and Historic Districts, along with an research index used during the writing process. Other highlights include an index to New York City landmarked buildings, an index to the Landmarks Preservation Commission diary, speech notes, and a few of Finnish architect Alvar Aalto's plans and photographs.
  - Alvar Aalto Plans and Photographs belonging to MOMA, undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - History Preserved: New York City Landmarks and Historic Districts Manuscript for Simon & Schuster, Inc., 1973 (Box 11)
  - Landmark Speech Notes, undated (Box 11)
  - Index for History Preserved: New York City Landmarks and Historic Districts, undated (Box 12)
  - Index to New York City Landmarked Buildings by Building Date, undated (Box 13)
  - Index to Landmarks Preservation Commission Diary, undated (Box 13)
- Series VI. Books and Pamphlets
  This series consists of published pamphlets dating from 1939 to 1985 that concern New York City. Some highlights include two World War II air raid precautions handbooks, a walking tour through Thomas Edison's "First District", a guide to New York City Landmarks, and a pamphlet on Landmark Preservation by John S. Pyke, Jr.
  This series also contains four published books. Three of the four books deal with the New York City Landmarks Preservation Commission, spanning from 1969 to 1973. The last book is Who's Who in the East (and Eastern Canada), The Eleventh Edition, and features Harmon Hendricks Goldstone.
  - Air Raid Precautions Handbooks: No. 5 - "Structural Defence" No. 5A - "Bomb Resisting Shelters", 1939 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - "Exploration of the Ways, Means and Values of Museum Communication with the Viewing Public", 1967 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - "A Guide to New York City Landmarks", 1979 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - "Where They Lit Up New York: A Walking Tour Through Thomas Edison's 'First District'", 1979 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - "Village Views" Vol. II No. 3, 1985 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - "Local Laws of the City of New York - Landmarks Preservation Commission", undated (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - "Landmark Preservation" by John S. Pyke, Jr., undated (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - "Map of the Bronx Zoo", undated (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Who's Who in the East (and Eastern Canada), The Eleventh Edition by Marquis-Who's Who, 1967 (Box 14, Object unknown container)
  - New York City Landmarks Preservation Commission Designation Reports, October 29, 1968 through July 29, 1969, 1968-1969
  - New York City Landmarks Preservation Commission Designation Reports, August 26, 1969 through April 19, 1973, 1969-1973 (Box 14, Object unknown container)
  - New York City Landmarks Preservation Commission Designation Reports, May 15, 1973 through December 18, 1973, 1979 (Box 14, Object unknown container)
- Series VII. Photography
  This series contains one folder and one photo album. The folder consists of a miscellaneous collection of photographs of events and buildings. The photo album is a collection of photographs from the Dorado Beach Hotel, which was designed by Harmon Hendricks Goldstone.
  - Photographs, undated (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Dorado Beach Hotel Photo Album, undated (Box 14, Object unknown container)
- Series VIII. Oversized Materials
  This series consists of miscellaneous oversized materials housed separately. The call phrase for these materials is Y- Goldstone, Harmon Hendricks.
  The Oversized Material series is located with the
  Oversize Manuscripts Collection, 1648-1998.
  - Chronological Chart of Designated Historical Landmarks, 1972 (Oversize Folder: Small)
  - "Proposed Building for Carnegie Endowment for International Peace", December 1949 (Oversize Folder: Small)
  - "Rebuilding Central Park: A Management and Restoration Plan" Draft Edition, 1985 (Oversize Folder: Small)
  - War Service Certification from the Office of Inter-American Affairs Awarded to Harmon Goldstone, undated (Oversize Folder: Small)
  - Drawing of 1107 Fifth Avenue, undated (Oversize Folder: Small)
  - "A Plan for Manhattan Civic Center", 1948 (Oversize Folder: Small)
  - Engineering Defense Training Course Given by the College of Engineering at New York University Certificate Awarded to Harmon Hendricks Goldstone; Training Course Entitled "Aerial Bombardment Protection", 1941 (Oversize Folder: Small)
  - Certificate of Life Membership to the New-York Historical Society Awarded to Harmon H. Goldstone, 1972 (Oversize Folder: Small)
  - Blueprints for 77 Bedford St., 1981 (Oversize Folder: Small)